[theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
[screaming]
[shattering sound]
[Ivy] Maybe this is exactly
what you deserve.
Bye, Corruption Queen.
You should take this opportunity
to assess your past actions.
And you can do it all
in the comfort of this jail.
Why are you punishing your own daughter?
-Just shut up!
-You'll meet your maker one day.
-Fifty million pesos.
-What do I get in return?
I will become king,
and you will be queen
of Poblacion Ardiente.
[Ivy] Yes, Congressman.
I'm with Sanggano right now,
and we're on our way
to deliver the money
to the district chairmen.
I'll do anything. Just get me out of here.
I'll even turn my back
on my worthless father.
If you aren't going to help Emilia,
you might as well tell her the truth!
That's right! Esmeralda wasn't
Emilia's mother.
I took Emilia away to punish her,
to make her feel the pain
that her mother put me through.
[Jose] We're being followed.
Don't you dare touch my money!
-Hey!
-Mister Fernan!
There's no way in hell you're
ever using my money, old man.
[Claire] I will tell her the truth.
So she can help Emilia break free
from a monster like you!
Mrs. Emilia, Jaguar ordered us to get you.
[Julio] Go after Clarita!
Shoot her if you have to!
But do not let her leave this place alive!
Esmeralda was not your real mother.
Aunt Claire!
[Damian] We have to take back
all the money
Raul stole from me.
[gasps]
Dante?
Dad?
[breathing heavily]
[sobs]
-[siren wailing]
-Auntie.
Emilia, we need to leave right now.
The cops will be here any minute.
No, Jaguar. We cannot leave my aunt here.
We can't!
Aunt Claire!
Emilia, we have to go!
It's dangerous out here.
No! No!
Jaguar, please!
Listen to me, Emilia.
I'm sorry for your loss,
but you aren't safe here.
The police are looking for you.
What about my aunt?
Aunt Claire!
Don't leave me!
[wailing]
Dad?
Lily…
Lily, he's not your father.
This isn't him.
He's your Uncle Damian,
your dad's brother.
Come on, dear. Let's take him home now.
He's Dad's brother?
[somber music playing]
[sobs]
Dad had a twin brother?
[sobbing]
[somber music playing]
You came all the way here
just to lecture me?
-Please, leave me alone.
-I am just concerned, Emilia.
Papa!
Why are you just standing there?
You have to do something.
-[Emilia] No!
-There's nothing I can do.
Auntie, don't tell me you're not
going to bail me out of here?
Why are you even here, then?
I just want to be here for you.
Auntie, it's not like I'm going to die.
[sobs]
She was the only person who understood me.
I would have gone completely mad
if it weren't for her.
And now that she's gone,
I don't know what to do.
Aunt Claire was one of the
kindest people I've ever known.
I love her so much.
I will always remember you.
Emilia.
That's enough.
We need to leave now
before the cops track us here.
I will order my men to take care
of things here for you.
You know, Jaguar…
my mom died when I was young.
And she was one of the only few
who really loved me.
She and the town were my whole life
because Papa never loved me.
But apparently,
she wasn't even my real mother.
My mom was the only one who loved me
the way Papa never did.
That's why I need to find
my real mother, Jaguar.
Please, help me.
[sobbing]
[crickets chirping]
[soft instrumental playing]
He looks exactly like Dad.
I was really taken aback.
It's almost as though
my father came back to life.
[soft music playing]
I do wonder, Mom…
if Dad were still around…
what kind of life would we have?
Would it be a peaceful one?
I mean, we'd be happy
because he'd be here.
[sighs]
After everything we went through…
you'd probably think I'm strong.
But to be honest, I get tired too.
I can't be strong all the time.
Come to think of it, if…
If Dad were still alive,
would he be pleased with what I'm doing?
Sometimes, I wonder…
Should I just continue what I started?
Then again, the pain is still there.
The pain they caused us is still there,
and it still hurts.
Sometimes, I wish we could just
leave everything behind…
and move somewhere else…
someplace where the two of us
can be happy.
I can only hope…
that Dad understands what I'm doing, Mom.
You're right, dear.
If your father were still around,
our lives would be different.
We wouldn't be going through all of this.
But that doesn't mean he'd be
against what we've been doing.
If he were still alive,
I'm sure that he'd be fighting
by our side.
Because there's no greater life
than one devoted to fighting
for the greater good.
A life where you put the good of others
above your own interests.
That's probably what
your father would say.
And if he were still around, dear…
I'm sure he'd be so proud of you.
[sighs]
Thank you, Jaguar.
Emilia, I'm here with you now.
You will never be alone again.
I know. But first things first.
I have to find out who killed Aunt Claire.
All right.
Did you burn the body?
Did you bury it?
Did you throw it in the river?
Or feed it to the dogs?
None of the above?
Then where the heck is Clarita's body?!
Well, listen up, morons.
Get out of here, and find her body.
You're not coming back here until you find
Clarita's rotting corpse.
I don't care if you have
to search every nook
and cranny of Poblacion Ardiente.
Go!
As for you, Colonel…
Have you handed the money to Miss Aguas?
I'm talking about the money
to be distributed
to the district chairmen
to buy the people's votes.
Congressman, Diego Torillo ambushed us.
He could surrender the money to the police
and find out about our operation.
You insolent piece of trash!
I gave you a simple job to do,
and you bungled it!
Get out of my sight!
Why am I surrounded by brainless people?!
I don't deserve this.
Why is Uncle Damian here?
And how did he get shot?
I hope I'm wrong.
But as far as I remember,
Damian caused nothing
but trouble for your father.
Our daughter is so pretty.
What would you like to name her?
-I was hoping to name her Lily.
-Lily?
Yes. Isn't that nice?
Damian.
Why are you here so early?
Did you skip class again?
Dante.
Damian, look at your niece.
We named her Lily.
What about you, Damian?
Don't you want to have your
own family like your brother?
I don't need a family.
What I need is to get rich.
That way, I can finally do you both proud.
How will you do that?
You're not even focused on your studies.
Why? Is school the only way
to succeed in life?
And cutting classes…
and living like a crook
will help you succeed in life?
[Camia] Dante, that's enough.
[door closes]
Lily, your father did everything he could
to get Damian on the right track.
But he chose to leave his family.
I just hope he's changed.
[crickets chirping]
Jepoy.
Jepoy, wait. Are you even listening to me?
-Anna…
-Where are you going?
Anna, please. I have to go.
But where are you going?
You've been gone for days,
and now you're leaving again?
I'm sorry, Anna. I just really need to go.
No, Jepoy. Just stay here
until Lily comes back.
Otherwise, I'd find out
where you're always off to
and whom you've been meeting up with.
[tense music playing]
[birds chirping]
Why do I have this sinking feeling…
that these incidents are connected?
[sighs]
Colonel.
Yes, Congressman?
I want you to investigate
how Emilia escaped from prison.
And don't show your face here
until you find out.
-Yes, Congressman.
-Okay.
[phone ringing]
Hello?
[tense music playing]
[soft instrumental playing]
Dad.
[groans]
[grunts]
Who are you? Why am I here?
Damian.
[tense music playing]
Emilia?
I'm glad you came, Papa.
We can finally lay Aunt Claire to rest.
[ominous music playing]
Surprised?
Not really.
I'm actually more surprised…
that it took you this long
to get out of jail.
Why didn't you help me?
-Emilia…
-Come on, Papa!
Why did you let me go to jail?
You even went after Aunt Claire too.
Preposterous.
There's no use denying it, Papa,
because your men are a bunch of failures!
Why did you have Aunt Claire killed?
Did you kill her to cover up some secret?
Now, you wait a minute.
Hold on!
Why am I suddenly on the hot seat?
The thing is, you've got a lot
of questions to answer too.
Let's play a game, shall we? It's called,
"You Tell Me Your Secrets,
And I'll Tell You Mine."
Let's start.
How, in heaven's name…
did my beautiful daughter,
a fugitive at that,
get out of jail?
Hmm?
[ominous music swelling]
Or should we just set aside
the question-and-answer portion
for much later?
Why don't we have… dinner at home?
It would be a more relaxing setting.
I'm sure you missed the mansion.
I'm glad you asked, Papa.
But first, I have to go somewhere.
Okay. Then let's leave
this morbid location.
Camia?
Damian.
I saw you on the street.
You were bleeding, so I helped you.
What are you doing here?
When Dante died, I thought you'd
never come back to this place.
It's a long story.
But, Damian, why didn't you
visit us when your brother died?
Dante! I need your help.
Get me out of here.
I've told you so many times,
but you still haven't changed.
We may be brothers, but I won't think
twice about having you locked up
if that's what it takes
to set you straight.
Some brother you turned out to be!
[laughs mockingly]
That's how Jaguar works.
If you're smart and sharp,
it'll rain cash!
PUBLIC ATTORNEY FOUND DEAD
IN POBLACION ARDIENTE
Are we still going to Poblacion Ardiente?
No. Let's go back.
I didn't go to his funeral
because he never cared for me, right?
Damian, that's not true. Dante loved you.
He did everything he could
to get you out of prison.
He worked on your case.
He came back for you,
but you were gone by then.
Dante, take it easy.
You'll ruin the surprise.
I can't wait to tell him
about the schedule of the trial.
This is his chance at freedom.
I know he will change for the better.
Sir, can I please talk to Damian Cruz?
Oh, he's gone. He escaped.
Believe me, your brother loved
you very much.
All he ever wanted
was for you to be happy.
[soft instrumental playing]
Damian.
I know how you feel.
[exhales]
I felt the same thing
when your brother died.
If you only knew how much
we suffered when he was gone.
Lily.
Damian.
This is Lily, my daughter.
She's your niece.
Lily?
It's okay, Lily.
Have a seat, Lily.
You've grown so much.
Damian, I need to ask you a favor.
Can you please not tell anyone
that you saw me and Lily?
Why not?
It's a long story,
but you'll find out soon enough.
Lily.
Um…
Uncle Damian, if you don't mind me asking…
what are you doing here
at Poblacion Ardiente?
And how did you get shot?
[tense music playing]
[gunshot]
[panting]
I was ambushed by an armed man.
He robbed me.
I didn't think armed goons
have become rampant here
in Poblacion Ardiente.
[groans]
You know, Uncle Damian, since…
you're new around here…
you should always be on guard.
This town is full of two-faced bastards.
They're very good
at putting up a good front,
but they will show their true
intentions soon enough.
They're the ones capable
of committing crimes.
Diego, this will be
your temporary headquarters.
You can't go back home yet.
Your money's safe and sound now.
Good thing Julio
didn't get his hands on it.
The money isn't important, Diego.
What matters is you're safe.
You're all safe.
[soft music playing]
Jepoy!
I'm glad you got away from Jaguar.
I needed to.
[phone ringing]
Excuse me.
Yes, Congressman?
Miss Aguas.
I heard what happened. Are you okay?
Well, Congressman, I'm trying
my best to cope with things.
Oh. Poor girl.
Why don't you come over?
I can help you recover and
you can see Emilia if you want.
Emilia?
Wait, Congressman, I thought
you had no plans
of bailing Emilia out.
[chuckles]
It's a long story.
Anyway, please do come. At about seven.
So we can have a small
get-together of sorts.
Excuse me. I need to go.
Diego, Anna, Jepoy.
[tense music playing]
Colonel, are you sure
Miss Aguas is responsible
for this screw-up?
Yes, I'm sure, Congressman.
Hmm.
In that case, we'll make her pay for it.
Oh, and please make sure
you find out where Emilia is.
I'm not done with her yet.
Seriously, these people…
Damian. You're finally awake.
Hold on, I'll make some breakfast.
[soft instrumental playing]
Whatever feelings you had,
that's all in the past.
You're not supposed to have feelings
for her anymore, Damian.
-It's her! It's her.
-Now's your chance.
-Hold this.
-I'm sure you'll back out again.
Me, back out? Shut up. I won't.
Hey! My bag!
-Hey!
-Call the cops!
Sir! Sir, that's enough!
Thank you. That's enough.
Let the police take care of him.
The police?
They'll just let him walk free
if he posts bail.
Got it?
People like him deserve
to have their hands chopped off!
Anyway, here's your bag.
-It's good as new, miss.
-Thank you.
I'm Damian, by the way.
-What's your name?
-Uh…
-Well?
-[Camia grunts]
-[Camia groans]
-[Damian] Oh.
-Camia.
-Camia?
You know, Camia, it's dangerous
around these parts.
Maybe I should walk you home.
-No, thank you. I can manage.
-Are you okay?
-Thank you.
-Are you sure?
-I hope you didn't get hurt.
-No.
-Can you walk?
-I'm fine, thank you.
What a beautiful name.
-Camia…
-Thank you.
Miss, are you all right?
I saw this man steal your bag.
You're twins?
No, we just look alike.
This is my older brother, Dante.
Dante, this is my friend, Camia.
Hi.
Do you want to report
the incident to the police?
[Dante] Just eat up.
I'm glad you came.
You skipped school again
because of your side gig.
You know that's illegal, right?
Dante, stop lecturing me already.
Let's just talk about
why you called me here.
What's this about?
It's about… Camia.
I want to court her.
[fork thumps]
That's all right with you, isn't it?
[Damian groans]
Damian, are you sure you don't
want to go to the hospital?
Uh…
No need. I'm fine.
Or are you just refusing
to go to the hospital
because you're on the run from the cops?
I've turned my life around, Camia.
Back in prison, I realized
that being a criminal is hard.
You don't have a future,
and the law will never be kind to you.
I've turned my back on
my old life since then.
[sighs]
All right, Damian.
I'll choose to believe you
because if Dante were still alive,
I'm sure he'd do the same thing.
Because he cares for you.
Thanks, Camia.
Ah…
Anyway, you should eat. The food is ready.
I'm sorry, Dante.
Looks like I won't just be
reclaiming Jaguar's identity.
I might have to take Camia
away from you too.
Eat up.
[tense music playing]
Here. This was your brother's favorite.
-It's okay, I'll do it.
-Just help yourself, okay?
Sure, thanks. Won't you join me?
Go ahead. I'll eat later. Thanks.
[tense music continues playing]
[tense music swelling]
Don't move around too much, Damian.
It might get worse.
Sorry for bothering you. And Lily too.
If you went to a clinic,
even to the one in town,
you'd heal up in no time.
I don't need to. You're here, anyway.
[groans]
You can take care of me.
Damian!
What's the real reason you're
here in Poblacion Ardiente?
When I got out of prison,
I set up a small business.
I had somebody else manage it.
But now, he doesn't want
to give turn it over back to me.
He's here in Ardiente,
that's why I'm here too.
It's dangerous here.
Especially for you.
What do you mean?
Damian, you look exactly like Dante.
If you aren't careful, they
might set their sights on you,
just like what they did to Dante.
What did the Ardientes do to Dante?
[tense music playing]
Dante was killed
by the most powerful family
in Poblacion Ardiente years ago.
Emilia Ardiente was the one behind it.
[Emilia] Jaguar.
I thought you weren't coming.
[tense music playing]
Ma'am, according to police
records in Manila,
Damian Cruz has been
on the run since 2004.
Here's his file.
And we've also confirmed
that Emilia Ardiente escaped.
I know. But how exactly?
How isn't the question, but who?
A few men helped her escape.
A group of men, and a masked man.
A masked man?
[tense music playing]
You don't have to go back home.
You can't trust your father.
If you go back there, I'm sure
he'll have you arrested himself.
I need to know the truth about my mother.
Emilia, you don't need to feel…
like something's missing in your life
just because you don't know
who your real mother is.
I'm here for you.
I can give you the love you never had.
-Emilia?
-Jaguar…
I want to see your face,
the face of my protector.
Why are you scared?
I'll accept you no matter who you are,
no matter what you look like.
Jaguar?
[reporter] With the upcoming
national elections
being held tomorrow,
Poblacion Ardiente will witness the race
between Congressman Julio Ardiente
and his grandson, Diego Ardiente-Torillo.
Who will you be voting for?
Thank you, people of Sto. Niño.
Just a reminder,
please don't forget to vote
at the elections tomorrow.
We shouldn't give in to the fear
that they're trying to sow in us
because we will make the voices
of the people of Ardiente be heard.
-That's right!
-Am I right?
[cheering]
-Diego!
Let them hear the people's voice!
To our victory!
Hey! Hey! Hey! Wait!
Hey! What's going on?
-It's Sanggano!
-Hey!
Hey! Listen up, everyone!
To everybody on this list,
if you don't vote for Julio Ardiente,
then you better not show up here tomorrow.
Is that clear?
[overlapping dialogue]
Hold on! What are you doing?
Who are you to deprive us
of our human rights?
You need to get out of our territory!
That's right! The Ardientes' minions
should never set foot here!
That's right!
They're just trying to scare us
because they failed to buy
the votes of the other town.
But we aren't scared of you!
-Is that so?
-Hey! Hey! Hey!
-Let go of me!
-You should be tied up!
Don't touch me! How dare you!
-Hey! You bastard!
-[people clamoring]
Come on! Come on! Is that all you've got?
-[crowd screams]
-Hey! Hey!
-Hey!
-[clamoring]
[Loring screams]
How could you even kill an old man?!
-What do you want?!
-You keep getting in our way!
The only reason you're still alive
after stealing from me
is that I chose not to get back at you.
Do you understand?
That money was never yours,
and you're never getting it back.
You better leave now or else!
Is that a threat? All right,
then. You asked for it.
-Come on. Fight me! Come at me!
-You can do it, Boss!
[Anna] Diego! Jepoy!
[crowd screams]
Diego, get up!
[man] Be careful, Diego!
[groans]
[clamoring]
[man] Out of the way! Out of the way!
If you don't want to ruin
Julio Ardiente's name,
then you better leave right now.
Leave!
-[man] Leave!
-[man 2] Get out of here!
[crowd clamoring]
-Go away!
-Leave!
Leave!
Get away from here!
Go!
Leave!
-Uncle Pandoy!
-I'm fine.
Uncle, are you okay?
Nanny, did they hurt you?
-No, I'm fine.
-Thank you.
-Anna, are you okay?
-I'm okay.
-Did anybody get hurt?
-No, we're fine.
What about you?
-I'm fine.
-Make sure those oafs are gone.
[tense music playing]
[Raul] If I tell you who I really am,
how can I be sure that you won't leave me?
Jaguar…
There's something you need to know.
[Camia] Diego, this is the day
we've been waiting for.
I will be the governor of this town.
To the future of Ardiente!
Diego!
[Julio] I have a plan.
And in this plan,
my victory will be certain.
We'll just have to blow things up.
[explosions]
[Julio] You're the bomb.
[laughing wickedly]
[theme music playing]